[
  {
    "question": "At which auto show are futuristic concepts often showcased?",
    "answer": "Geneva Motor Show"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can you identify a clutch malfunction?",
    "answer": "Slipping"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many cylinders does the engine of the Mercedes-Benz 300SEL 6.3 have?"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many days does a car show typically last on average?",
    "answer": "5-10"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many liters of fuel does the tank of an average motorcycle hold?"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many members are there on average in a vintage car club?",
    "answer": "1000+"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many teams participate in the World Endurance Championship (WEC)?",
    "answer": "10"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many types of vehicles are involved?",
    "answer": "Four"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many years has the 24 Hours of Le Mans race been held?",
    "answer": "Since 1923"
  },
  {
    "question": "How to adjust a carburetor?",
    "answer": "According to the manual"
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year was the Bugatti brand founded?",
    "answer": "1909"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city is the Formula 1 Grand Prix held on a street circuit in Asia?",
    "answer": "Singapore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the engine control unit.",
    "answer": "ECU"
  },
  {
    "question": "What actions should be taken during hydroplaning?",
    "answer": "Release the accelerator"
  },
  {
    "question": "What benefit do manufacturers gain from participating in auto shows?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What can cause the 'Check Engine' light to turn on?",
    "answer": "Engine problems"
  },
  {
    "question": "What car does Brian drive in the movie 'Fast and Furious'?",
    "answer": "Nissan Skyline"
  },
  {
    "question": "What controls the fuel supply to the engine?",
    "answer": "ECU"
  },
  {
    "question": "What controls the transitions between engines?",
    "answer": "Controller"
  },
  {
    "question": "What determines the engine's operating mode?",
    "answer": "ECU"
  },
  {
    "question": "What device allows you to record changes in the throttle position?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What device controls the fuel supply in an engine?",
    "answer": "Fuel injectors"
  },
  {
    "question": "What distance do motorcycles typically cover in a day?",
    "answer": "800-900 km"
  },
  {
    "question": "What distinguishes a sportbike from other types of motorcycles?",
    "answer": "Speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does 'turbocharger upgrade' mean?",
    "answer": "Increase in pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the choice of car wheels depend on?",
    "answer": "Wheel size"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the word 'enduro' mean?",
    "answer": "Off-road motorcycle"
  },
  {
    "question": "What economic benefit do hybrid cars offer?",
    "answer": "Fuel savings"
  },
  {
    "question": "What effect does a polyurethane suspension kit provide?",
    "answer": "Improved stiffness"
  },
  {
    "question": "What engine did the first Buick Roadmaster have?",
    "answer": "Straight-eight"
  },
  {
    "question": "What ensures optimal engine performance?",
    "answer": "ECU"
  },
  {
    "question": "What ensures the safety of competition participants?",
    "answer": "Police officers"
  },
  {
    "question": "What helps maintain the stable operation of a motorcycle?",
    "answer": "Timely maintenance"
  },
  {
    "question": "What helps reduce the weight of a car for better fuel efficiency?",
    "answer": "Composite materials"
  },
  {
    "question": "What helps to avoid accidents at an intersection?",
    "answer": "Following traffic rules"
  },
  {
    "question": "What improves fuel efficiency during braking?",
    "answer": "Regenerative braking"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a 'dry clutch' in a motorcycle?",
    "answer": "Without lubrication"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a Head-Up Display system?",
    "answer": "Projection of information onto the windshield"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a motocross bike?",
    "answer": "For off-road"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a torque converter?",
    "answer": "Transmission of torque"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is actively being developed in electric vehicles to increase their range?",
    "answer": "Batteries"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is done during engine diagnostics?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the engine displacement of the Ducati Panigale V4 (cc)?",
    "answer": "1103"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the engine displacement of the Porsche 992 Turbo S?",
    "answer": "3.8 liters"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the function of an intercooler?",
    "answer": "Cooling the air"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main feature of a motocross bike?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main focus of the auto show in Las Vegas?",
    "answer": "Tuning"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the mechanism called that regulates the intake and exhaust of gases in an engine?",
    "answer": "Valve timing"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the minimum safe distance between cars in winter?",
    "answer": "More than two seconds"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the mode of driving using only the electric motor called?",
    "answer": "EV"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name for a group of motorcyclists traveling together?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of a race on a track?",
    "answer": "Circuit Race"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of a zigzag road in the mountains?",
    "answer": "Serpentine"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the club for Jaguar car owners?",
    "answer": "Jaguar Enthusiasts' Club"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the oil cooling system?",
    "answer": "Oil cooler"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the race track in Austria?",
    "answer": "Spielberg"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the sport touring model from Kawasaki?",
    "answer": "Concours"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the sports car series from Toyota?",
    "answer": "GR"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the system that assists with lane changing?",
    "answer": "Lane Change Assist"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the system that recognizes road signs?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the penalty for driving under the influence?",
    "answer": "High"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the racing category for cars with hybrid powertrains in European championships called?",
    "answer": "LMP1"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the screen called that displays information on a car's windshield?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the significance of LIDAR for autonomous vehicles?",
    "answer": "Navigation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the speed limit on some sections of a rally?",
    "answer": "140 km/h"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the speed of pit stops in F1?",
    "answer": "less than 3 seconds"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the system called that controls a motorcycle at low speeds?",
    "answer": "Stabilization"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the system called that supports optimal engine performance?",
    "answer": "Engine management system"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the technique called for safely navigating turns on a motorcycle?",
    "answer": "Countersteering"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the technology for fast charging electric vehicles called?",
    "answer": "DC Fast Charging"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the technology for recognizing traffic signs called?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the top speed of the 1963 Volvo P1800?",
    "answer": "175 km/h"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the top speed of the Chevrolet Corvette ZR1?",
    "answer": "345 km/h"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the top speed of the Lamborghini Huracán Performante?",
    "answer": "325 km/h"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the type of engine with a rotating piston called?",
    "answer": "Rotary"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is torque used for?",
    "answer": "Acceleration"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is used to treat rust on metal?",
    "answer": "Rust remover"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is worn out if a motorcycle brakes poorly?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What material is replacing metal in modern cars?",
    "answer": "Carbon"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method can be used to check the tightness of the cooling system?",
    "answer": "Pressure"
  },
  {
    "question": "What method can be used to test a battery?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What should be checked when there are malfunctions in motorcycle electronics?",
    "answer": "Battery"
  },
  {
    "question": "What should you do in case of a brake fluid leak?",
    "answer": "Replace the hoses"
  },
  {
    "question": "What system helps keep a motorcycle in a horizontal position?",
    "answer": "stabilizer"
  },
  {
    "question": "What technology allows cars to exchange data?",
    "answer": "V2V"
  },
  {
    "question": "What technology helps control battery energy consumption?",
    "answer": "Energy management"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of cooling is used in Ducati Panigale V4 engines?",
    "answer": "Liquid cooling"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of engine operates on various types of fuel?"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of hybrid cars is the most common?",
    "answer": "Full hybrids"
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of wheels improves handling?",
    "answer": "Alloy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the horsepower of the Dodge Viper V10 engine?",
    "answer": "450 hp"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the first American production car?",
    "answer": "Duryea Motor Wagon"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the first production car?",
    "answer": "Benz Patent-Motorwagen"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the front-wheel-drive car from Alfa Romeo?",
    "answer": "Alfasud"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the New York Auto Show begin?",
    "answer": "1900"
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the first hybrid cars appear?",
    "answer": "Late 1990s"
  },
  {
    "question": "When should you brake on a wet road?",
    "answer": "In advance"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are hybrid cars most commonly used?",
    "answer": "Urban transportation"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where are next year's car models first unveiled?",
    "answer": "New York Auto Show"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Mercedes-Benz model is considered a symbol of automotive design from the 1930s?",
    "answer": "500K"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which auto show is famous for the debut of new electric vehicles?",
    "answer": "Frankfurt IAA"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which automotive community is known for its gatherings with sports cars around the world?",
    "answer": "International Sports Car Club"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which brand created the first mass-produced electric car?",
    "answer": "Nissan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which brand manufactures Atlantis motorcycles?",
    "answer": "Benelli"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which brand manufactures the Concours touring motorcycles?",
    "answer": "Kawasaki"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which brand produced the Cord 810 model?",
    "answer": "Cord"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which brand produces sports models with the 'Z' badge?",
    "answer": "Nissan"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which car is considered the most successful in WRC history?",
    "answer": "Citroën C4"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which car manufacturer is associated with the legendary Countach model?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which car manufacturer produces the Aventador model?",
    "answer": "Lamborghini"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which car model has a hybrid engine?",
    "answer": "Porsche 918"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which category of vehicles has been participating in the rally since 2021?",
    "answer": "Classic"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company developed the HEMI engine?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company manufactures cars under the Genesis brand?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company manufactures the Continental GT motorcycle?",
    "answer": "Royal Enfield"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company manufactures the XC60 model?",
    "answer": "Volvo"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company merged with Rapp Motorenwerke in 1916 to become Bayerische Motoren Werke?",
    "answer": "BMW"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company produced the 'Pagoda' model in the 1960s?",
    "answer": "Mercedes-Benz"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company released the Defender model?",
    "answer": "Land Rover"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company was the first to create an automatic transmission?",
    "answer": "General Motors"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which component improves brake cooling?",
    "answer": "Air ducts"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which component is responsible for the movement of an electric vehicle?",
    "answer": "Electric motor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which component regulates the airflow in an engine?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country was the first to introduce electric buses?",
    "answer": "China"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which driver became the world champion in 2005 and 2006?",
    "answer": "Fernando Alonso"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which engine component creates a spark?",
    "answer": "Spark plug"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which engine component is responsible for fuel delivery and metering?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which event includes the Hillclimb race?",
    "answer": "Festival of Speed"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ignition system does not require spark plugs?",
    "answer": "Diesel"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which model is known as a powerful sportbike from Suzuki?",
    "answer": "Hayabusa"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which model is produced by Lexus?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which motorcycle brand is associated with a monocoque?",
    "answer": "MV Agusta"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which motorcycle component forces air into the cylinders?",
    "answer": "Turbocharger"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which motorcycle component is responsible for supplying oil?",
    "answer": "Pump"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which motorcycle is often used for riding on snow?",
    "answer": "Snowbike"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which motorcycle is used for racing and has more power?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which motorcycle was originally intended for police use?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which motorcyclist won the Dakar Rally 5 times in a row?",
    "answer": "Cyril Despres"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which new brand introduced the supercar Valkyrie?",
    "answer": "Aston Martin"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organization organizes events for retro cars?",
    "answer": "RetroFan Club"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which parameter increases the efficiency of electric vehicle batteries?",
    "answer": "Density"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which racing team is based in Woking?",
    "answer": "McLaren"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sensor measures the mass air flow?",
    "answer": "MAF"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which show is famous for debuting new luxury cars?",
    "answer": "Geneva Motor Show"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which show is known for electric vehicle debuts?",
    "answer": "Beijing Auto Show"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sports car is known as the Vette?",
    "answer": "Corvette"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which system controls the operation of the engine and transmission?",
    "answer": "ECU"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which system forces air into the engine cylinders?",
    "answer": "Turbocharging"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team has the most Constructors' Championship titles in Formula 1?",
    "answer": "Ferrari"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team uses Renault engines?",
    "answer": "Alpine"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which technology helps to increase battery capacity?",
    "answer": "Regen Braking"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which technology supports energy recuperation?",
    "answer": "Recuperator"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which track is known as the 'Green Hell'?",
    "answer": "Nürburgring"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which wrench is used to adjust the clutch?",
    "answer": "Box-end wrench"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created the classic Fiat 500?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who designed the legendary BMW 507?",
    "answer": "Albrecht von Goertz"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is a multiple-time WRC champion?"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the largest manufacturer of batteries for electric vehicles?",
    "answer": "CATL"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the primary buyer of electric vehicles?",
    "answer": "Urban residents"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first World Rally Championship (WRC) champion?",
    "answer": "Björn Waldegård"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the 2020 Italian Grand Prix?",
    "answer": "Pierre Gasly"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the Formula 1 World Championship in 2008?",
    "answer": "Lewis Hamilton"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the first Formula E race?",
    "answer": "Lucas di Grassi"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do hybrid cars cause less harm to the environment?",
    "answer": "Less emissions"
  }
]